<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>techinfo.gerull.nl</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/</link><description>Recent content on techinfo.gerull.nl</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 23:01:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techinfo.gerull.nl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Static Generator</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/new-static-generator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 23:01:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/new-static-generator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here we go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I start testing &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;, a new static site generator written in go. Or better &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Hugo&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every now and them I need something new to play with. As Jekyll is the most
established generator it is also the slowest. The progress of new development
is also not very speedy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Run a WordPress site on AWS</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/run-a-wordpress-site-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 20:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/run-a-wordpress-site-on-aws/</guid><description>I don’t want to purchase a hosting packet, as they are often quite restrictive. On the other hand I want to run a WordPress site but not on my local servers as that will require a lot of effort and investment in security setup.
As a DevOps engineer it is a nice a challenge to run my WordPress instance in the cloud. The starting point will be AWS Lightsail platform, as the monthly costs are quite reasonable.</description></item><item><title>Linux NFS server</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/linux-nfs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 11:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/linux-nfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Configuring a Network File System (NFS) server on Linux can be a valuable tool for sharing files and resources among multiple systems on a network. With NFS, clients can access files and directories on the server as if they were local, making it an ideal solution for organizations that need to share large amounts of data between multiple machines. In this article, we will guide you through the steps to set up an NFS server on Linux, including how to install and configure the necessary software, set up file sharing permissions, and troubleshoot common issues that may arise during the process. Whether you’re an experienced Linux user or just starting out, this guide will help you get up and running with NFS in no time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Java keystore</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/java-keystore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/java-keystore/</guid><description>&lt;p>Once in a while I have to change / add certificates to the Java keystore. Here is my memory support.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docker Swarm tricks</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/docker-swarm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 14:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/docker-swarm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tools and settings to help you run Docker Swarm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Development tools</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/dev-tools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 16:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/dev-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>These are my development tools for the different platforms I use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mostly development scripts and tools in Python or Javascript. My IDE of choice is Visual Studio Code because it covers all languages I need. You even get a decent milage using VS Code with Java.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vagrant template</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/vagrant-template/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 07:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/vagrant-template/</guid><description>&lt;p>Use Hashicorp Vagrant to nstall and run a virtual machine on your host.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Install and configure automount on CentOS 7</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/automount-on-centos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 10:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/automount-on-centos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recipe to configure the automount feature on RedHat / CentOS7 Linux.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Install a recent Git on CentOS 7</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-on-centos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 08:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-on-centos/</guid><description>&lt;p>CentOS 7 as well as RedHat 7 has very old Git version (1.8.x) in the official repositories. The
most tools I use need at least Git &amp;gt; 2.0.
In this post I will describe in brief how to update your Git installation. Here I will describe just two
of the possbile solutions. Install from source and install from the &lt;a href="https://ius.io/">IUS&lt;/a> repositories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Convert Mercurial to Git repositories</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/mercurial2git/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 13:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/mercurial2git/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please follow the excellent description on the &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Git-and-Other-Systems-Migrating-to-Git">Git documentation&lt;/a>. Here are some personal additions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reorganize physical volumes</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/reorg-partitions-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 08:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/reorg-partitions-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>These description is written for Ubuntu Linux. With a bit of creativity it should also work for other Linux flavours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Confluence recipe</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/confluence-recipe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 08:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/confluence-recipe/</guid><description>&lt;p>This instructions assume that Confluence is installed in &lt;code>/opt/confluence&lt;/code> and the data directory is &lt;code>/var/confluence&lt;/code>. The installation is on Ubuntu Linux but should also work on other flavours of Linux. Confluence requires a supported database, in this instruction I assume that the database is already configured.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jira recipe</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/jira-recipe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 17:37:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/jira-recipe/</guid><description>&lt;p>This instruction assumes that Jira is installed in &lt;code>/opt/jira&lt;/code> and the data directory is &lt;code>/var/jira&lt;/code>. The
installation is on Ubuntu Linux but should also work on other flavours of Linux.
Jira requires a supported database, in this instruction I assume that the database is already configured.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use large files with git-lfs</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-lfs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 07:13:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-lfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>GitHub has a repository upload limit of 100MB.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>The maximum size of Git objects that can be pushed to repositories on this appliance. Allowing large objects to be pushed into Git can degrade performance, consider other options (e.g. git-lfs) before increasing this value.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Use ssh agent on Mac OS</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/ssh-agent-on-mac/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 22:44:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/ssh-agent-on-mac/</guid><description>&lt;p>I ran into &amp;ldquo;ssh_askpass: exec(/usr/X11R6/bin/ssh-askpass): No such file or directory&amp;rdquo; errors using Git on a Mac with SSH. The ssh-askpass command used by Git is missing on a Mac. Using Git in Terminal (with bash) will prompt for the passphrase but using Git in VSCode will raise the mentioned error.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(My) Solution is to create a SSH agent in my .bashrc. Now the passphrase in my keychain will be used during Git operations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Merge 2 Git repositories</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-merge-2-repos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-merge-2-repos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes it is necessary to combine 2 different Git repositories with preservation of both histories. In this example I assume that we only have one active branch (master) around that none of the files are duplicates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Git rebase</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-rebase/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 22:23:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-rebase/</guid><description>&lt;p>The git rebase command is one of the more powerfull and advanced commands. You can use it to avoid overly complex merge operations. The common practice in Git is to do lot&amp;rsquo;s of small commit&amp;rsquo;s. But when your code builds fine and you don&amp;rsquo;t need that detailed piece of history anymore, you can compact these small commits into one or two big commits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ultimate source and authority on all Git commands is &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2">&lt;em>Pro Git&lt;/em>&lt;/a> the Git book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HA Proxy as a reverse ssh proxy</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/ha-proxy-for-ssh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/ha-proxy-for-ssh/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you want to hide a ssh service to the public use a reverse ssh proxy. Just
as Apache can act as a reverse http / https proxy, so can HA Proxy act as a
reverse ssh proxy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Git for Ubuntu</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/git-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>&lt;p>Running a recent Git for Ubuntu can sometimes be problematic. The Git version in the offical Ubuntu archives lags behind the maintainers, stable, version. To solve this install the Maintainers team version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shrink logic volumes</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/shrink-logical-volumes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/shrink-logical-volumes/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this post I will point out the steps to shrink logic volumes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Expand logic volumes</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/expand-logical-volume/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/expand-logical-volume/</guid><description>&lt;p>Logical volumes are easy to extend. The basic steps are like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Volume layout</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/linux-volume-layout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/linux-volume-layout/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s my personal preference for an allround Linux box. The following volume
layout is a baseline. If the machine is a server reduce /home and add much more
to /var where normally you data lives. For a development box increase /home
for all your projects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linux File System</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/linux-file-systems/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/posts/linux-file-systems/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is just a short example how I use the Linux file system. A full discussion with lot&amp;rsquo;s of links you will find on &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Filesystem_Hierarchy_Standard" title="Wikipedia">Wikipedia&lt;/a>. The home of the Linux File System Hierarchy is &lt;a href="http://www.pathname.com/fhs/" title="FHS">here&lt;/a>.
The layout below is the (almost) default of Debian and Ubuntu distributions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://techinfo.gerull.nl/about/</guid><description>I maintain this site as place to store cheat sheets, procedures and descriptions. Some of them I use so seldom that it&amp;rsquo;s not worthwhile to memorize them. Other&amp;rsquo;s are instructions I use for customers and are interesting enough to share. In short, you can read this site as an itinerary of my travels through Information Technology.
Publishing them all in a public place will help others too.
Myself Living and working in the Netherlands, I&amp;rsquo;m in the IT over 30 years now.</description></item></channel></rss>